A Guide to the Carl Sandburg Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8375-g
Carl Sandburg Collection 1929-1935
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8375-g
21 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1991 November 20
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Poem: " Grass, " by Carl Sandburg, 1929; AMsS, 1 p.
    [Handwritten by Albert Barrows and inscribed to him by the author.]
  - Poem: "Untitled," by Carl Sandburg, 1931 Nov; TMs, 1 p.
    [With "Nov. 1931 Chicago" written beneath the text in Albert Barrows' hand.]
  - Untitled Poem: "Edith is a flower of Albert's...," by Carl Sandburg, TMs, 1 p.
- Letters
  - Carl Sandburg to Albert Barrows, 1929 Jun 27; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for his letter and hopes to meet him sometime.]
  - Carl Sandburg to "Friend Barrows" [ Albert Barrows], 1929 Jul 16; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says Albert Barrows' letters are more poetic than his poems themselves.]
  - Albert Barrows to Carl Sandburg, 1929 Jul 21; TL, 2 p.
    [Explains his positions on humanity, civilization, and aesthetics, and defends his poems.]
  - Carl Sandburg to "Brother Barrows" [ Albert Barrows], 1929 Aug 19; TLS, 1 p.
    [Writes that his impressions of Albert Barrows' poems were only one man's, and hopes that one day they can sit down and talk things over.]
  - Carl Sandburg to "Brother Barrows" [ Albert Barrows], 1930 Oct 1; TLS, 1 p. (ec)
    [Is reading
    Pilgrims at the Shrine
    and is sending another fool book this month (original letter tipped into Sandburg's
    Early Moon
    , Barrett PS3537.A618 E3 1930, Rare Books Division).]
  - Albert Barrows to "Brother Sandburg" [ Carl Sandburg], 1930 Oct 7; ALS, 2 p.
    [Encloses an autobiographical tale whose writing was interrupted by illness, looks forward to receiving the book, with typed note from Proverbs on reverse.]
  - "C.S." [ Carl Sandburg] to "A.B." [ Albert Barrows], 1930; AN, 2 p.
    [Note describing the two as "battered strugglers" and enclosing photographs, with a note in Albert Barrows' hand indicating date.]
  - "Carl" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Brother Barrows" [ Albert Barrows], 1931 Jan 25; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for Potato Face drawings, says he will send poems, says his eyes and teeth are giving him trouble.]
  - "Sandburg" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Friend Barrows" Albert Barrows, [1931] Jun 25; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for the Potato Face letter, will read the story.]
  - "Carl" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Brother Barrows" Albert Barrows, 1932 Mar 14; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for his funny hospital letter, says it was forwarded to him at the University of Miami. ]
  - "Carl" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Brother Barrows" [ Albert Barrows], 1933 Apr 10; TLS, 2 p.
    [Conveys sympathy for Albert Barrows' pain, thanks him for prints and says he will send prints of the only two stereoscopic photographs of Lincoln known to exist.]
  - "Sandburg" [ Carl Sandburg to "Brother Barrows" [ Albert Barrows], 1934 Jan 12; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says he will be in San Francisco the last week in February, and that Albert Barrows and Ernst Bacon should read the January number of
    Fortune
    magazine for a long poem there.]
  - Howard Couper to Carl Sandburg, 1934 Mar 5; TLS, 1 p.
    [Letter marked "Copy," asks for permission to produce his choral adaptations of Carl Sandburg's verse.]
  - "Opakapakaa" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Potato" [ Albert Barrows], 1934 Mar 28; Telegram, 1 p.
    [Says "Aloha."]
  - "Carlo" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Albert" [ Albert Barrows], 1934 Apr 14; TLS, 1 p.
    [Trip made safely, visit to he and Edith [Barrows] high point, sending books.]
  - "Carlo" [ Carl Sandburg to "Albert" [ Albert Barrows], 1934 Apr 16; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks Albert Barrows for photographs, asks for copies for his publishers, encloses a letter from "one of our fellow strugglers" (see Howard Couper's of 1934 Mar 5) and mentions the Castine correspondence.]
  - "Carlo" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Albert" Albert Barrows], 1934 Jun 1; TLS, 1 p.
    [Says the typed sheets came, encloses a check for the typists' bill, says his main job here "drags and sags."]
  - "Carl" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Albert" Albert Barrows, 1934 Oct 1; TLS, 1 p.
    [Hopes and prays Albert Barrows' shingles are getting better, sends "rudabaga aloha and smoke-and-steel love" to he and Edith [Barrows]. ]
  - "Carl" [ Carl Sandburg] to "Albert" [ Albert Barrows], 1935 Mar 1; TLS, 1 p.
    [Was reminded of Albert Barrows and Edith [Barrows] by Lake Michigan's ice formations, sends photographs, and invites the Barrows for a visit.]